# Hi 👋 I'm Vasily Zubarev









I am a backend developer from Berlin 🟴

I adore technologies and building new things out of them. My startup background has given me a solid experience in designing systems from scratch and scale them, quickly adapting to the crazy world, thinking a few steps ahead, hiring and leading small teams if it's needed to get our things done.

I always try to keep up with the latest trends, but I prefer to build things as stupid as possible, because this is the only way they can evolve into something bigger.

### My main buzzwords



#### Experience

Platform Developer @ Anaconda, Inc. — Berlin, Germany + Austin, TX, USA Nov 2019 - Present



Well-known data-science platform.

- Our small team made <u>Team Edition</u> hosted package repository for companies
- I took the lead in developing a CVE vulnerability analysis system for these packages
- Bootstrapped Anaconda Nucleus the SaaS platform for data scientists and "the next big thing" in Anaconda world
- Developed a stateless, trusted and decentralized authorization system for microservices on OAuth, JWTs, IAM and Envoy-sidecarsh in Kubernetes

# **Software Engineer in Logistics @ Delivery Hero SE** — Berlin, Germany Sep 2018 — Nov 2019



Food delivery company. Logistics department — the heart of everything!

- Participated in the development of delivery timing and pricing service
- Finally immersed into the DevOps ideology. Managed infrastructure as code in kubernetes, helm and terraform. We had CI and CD for 40+ countries!
- Managed geometries and routing on PostGIS, OpenStreetMap and Shapely

## **Lead Backend Developer @ Sola.ai (aka. Plag)** — Vilnius, Lithuania 2014 — 2018



Decentralized social network based on Blockchain, IPFS and geolocation where people could earn coins on their content.

- Developed an asynchronous backend in Python, Asyncio, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Redis and AWS
- Dealt with Blockchain hype and \$2.5 million ICO (pretty intense!)
- Built a decentralized content delivery network using IPFS and DHT
- Implemented a smart newsfeed that heavily used geolocation and recommendation engine features
- Managed a small team of developers at the period of company's growth
- We had a lot of problems with fraud and we were actively defending ourselves against it right on the air. Fun time!

## **Developer and Researcher @ Sensee** — Vilnius, Lithuania 2014 — 2016



Real-time video communication app with AR features. We started it with the same team as the previous project.

- Designed and built an asynchronous backend for 10,000+ simultaneous connections using Tornado (popular async framework at the time) and Websockets (not so popular that time:D)
- Implemented a peer-to-peer video and data transmission system using WebRTC that dramatically saved costs for infrastructure

 Using OpenCV, I've developed a real-time object detection algorithm which was ported to iOS and Android by C++ developers, which I helped to interview and hire

### **Backend Developer @ We Heart Pics** — Moscow, Russia [Remote] 2012 — 2014



Instagram-like social network with daily photo-challenges for 2M users.

- Inherited a monolithic API on Python, Django, MySQL, AWS and continued its development until the very end
- The project was changing often and its admin interface was constantly breaking down. So I've created an automatic admin generator called GodMode and open-sourced it later

## **Freelance Web Developer** — Novosibirsk, Russia 2009 — 2012



Full-stack web development for food while studying in university.

#### Education

#### **Novosibirsk State Technical University**

Master's Degree with honours 2008 - 2014

Actively engaged in research on Natural Language Processing and Search Engines. Wrote a thesis: *Adaptive semantic text analysis algorithm for a formalised search query building.* In human language, I built a parser for turning text into a tree structure, which can be processed by a search engine. Like a heart for Siri or Alexa.

#### Personal info

Male, 29 y.o., originally from Siberia Russia. Moved to Lithuania in 2014, and in 2018 to Berlin, where I am still today. Really love this crazy place.

Hobbies: taking photos, travelling, blogging, mountain biking and building my VW bus

#### Languages:

- English C1
- German B1
- Russian native

Wish to learn Chinese or at least Spanish:)

Pet-projects on GitHub: vas3k.club, Infomate, Pepic

#### Some of my articles:

- Computational Photography. From Selfies to Black Holes
- A Team. How to build awesome teams without bullshit
- Machine Learning for Everyone
- How Machines Predict The Weather For Us
- Machine Translation. From the Cold War to Deep Learning